pathoma.com 2018-06-10

# Privacy Policy | Pathoma

**Pathoma™ Privacy Policy** – Last updated: June 7, 2011.

Pathoma LLC (“Pathoma”, “we”, “us” or “our”) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This policy guides how we collect, store and use information about our customers and Site visitors. By visiting the Pathoma.com domain, or any related sub-domains (collectively “Site”), or otherwise accessing our services (“Services”), you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. As we continue to improve the Service, materials and the features we provide, this Privacy Policy is subject to change. If there are changes or additions to this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here or in other formats for you to review. If we change our Privacy Policy in such a way that your personal information may be used or shared in a manner not described in the Privacy Policy at the time you provided it, we will give you the opportunity to opt-out of having your information used or shared in that new manner. By visiting our Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy and otherwise are required to accept our Terms of Use which can be found at <http://www.pathoma.com/terms>. You may not use our Site if you have not read, understood and agreed to our Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy.

**WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT CUSTOMERS DOES PATHOMA GATHER**

The information we learn from customers helps us personalize and continually improve your experience with Pathoma. Here are the types of information we gather.

**Information You Give Us.** We receive and store any information you enter on our Site or give us in any other way. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customizing future products for you, improving our offerings and communicating with you. Please be aware that if you disclose information on Site message boards or chat areas, that information may be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited communications from third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of Pathoma. Such information that you may give to us may include:

  * Your name, postal address, telephone numbers, and email address.
  * Your billing information, such as credit card numbers provided to make a purchase.
  * Information you submit to us in the form of comments or other Site postings, or simple questions or feedback you provide to us.
  * Information about your interests, including the specific services or products we provide to you, and the options and offers you select.

**Your Choices.** We collect your information when you send us inquiries, make purchases, submit content to the Site in any way, via mail, email or over the phone, as well as when you submit information on forms that exist on our Site. You can choose not to provide us with certain information and can visit our Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personally identifiable information about yourself. However, that may result in your not being able to use certain features of our Services or inaccurate transaction results because such information may be required in order to use those features.

**Service and Account Information.** We may also track Services activity for the purposes of maintaining user accounts, user and customer support, targeted recommendations to you, notice of special events and opportunities and managing the operation of our Services.

**Usage Data.** We also collect information in the form of log files that are generated during transactions with the Services, including usage patterns, IP addresses, browser type, browsing, and the frequency of use of certain Services.

**E-mail Communications**. To help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from Pathoma if your computer supports such capabilities.

**Automatic Information**. We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many web sites, we use “cookies,” and we obtain certain types of information when your web browser accesses the Site or other content served by or on behalf of Pathoma on other web sites.

**USE OF THIS INFORMATION**

When you supply information about yourself for a specific purpose, we use the information for only that purpose (such as to provide the service or information you have requested). In general, Pathoma collects personal information when you use our Services for the following purposes:

  * To verify your identity;
  * To create and maintain your user Account;
  * To answer email we receive from you;
  * To protect against or identify fraudulent transactions;
  * To enforce our terms and conditions;
  * To deliver our Services;
  * To provide customer services;

  * To improve the effectiveness of our Services;
  * To contact you regarding our Services unless you elected not to receive these communications;
  * For our marketing endeavors, including, but not limited to, sending marketing communications, success stories and performing other business activities as needed;
  * To generally manage our business; and
  * To perform other functions, which we will describe to you at the time we collect the information.

Should any material changes be made to the ways in which we use personally identifiable information, Pathoma will take commercially reasonable measures to inform you. We will also post the changes to our use of personally identifiable information on our Site.

**WHAT ABOUT COOKIES**

Like the operators of most web sites, we may use tracking software and similar technology, which automatically collects information about your computer hardware, software and use of the Services. This information may be used by us for the operation of the Services and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Services. Many commercial web site operators collect this information in similar ways. However, this information is not linked to any of your personal information. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide additional features. As is standard practice on many web sites, the Site utilizes cookies to gather technical information. Generally speaking, it records data about your computer’s navigation within our Site (pages viewed, date and time of your visit, etc.), which are read during subsequent visits. Cookies provide web sites with information regarding the state your browser is in.

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on’s settings or visiting the Web site of its manufacturer. However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of the Site’s essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you may not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or use any the Site’s products and services that require you to Sign In.

**DOES PATHOMA SHARE THE INFORMATION IT RECEIVES**

Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it or sharing it with others. We share customer information only as described below and with companies which are subject to this Privacy Policy or follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Policy.

**Third-Party Service Providers**. We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), processing credit card payments and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

**Your Participation.** When you participate in a promotion, we may share your personal information with business partners offering the products, services, promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes. We will remind you of this in any registration form used to participate in any such promotion. We won’t share your personal information with these businesses unless you choose to participate in their offer or program. When you choose to engage in a particular offer or program, you authorize us to share your email address and other information with the relevant business partner.

**Business Transfers**. As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that Pathoma LLC, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

**Your Posts**. Any personally identifiable information you submit on a forum board, blog, comment about the Site, or any other public forum on our Site can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We recommend that you do not provide your name, email address or any other personal information. You may not provide the names, email addresses or other personal information of any other person in such postings. Please note that if you choose to do so, it is at your own risk and you accept full responsibility for those posts and any consequences that may arise from posting this information.

**Protection of Pathoma and Others**. We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate in response to a legal process or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency, to establish or exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims or otherwise comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Pathoma, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Non-Personal Information**. We may share your non-personal information in any of the above circumstances. Also, we may share aggregated non-personal information with third parties, including advisors, advertisers and investors, for general business analysis purposes. For example, we may provide our advertisers or partners with the number of visitors to our Site and the most popular features or services accessed. This information does not contain any personal information. It may be used to develop and deliver targeted Services or advertising on our Site and on websites of third parties.

**HOW SECURE IS INFORMATION ABOUT ME**

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. You should feel confident using our Site. However, no system can be completely secure. Although we take very significant steps to secure your information that is under our control and appropriately limit access to it, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us by email, and you do so at your own risk.

**INFORMATION ABOUT OTHER PRODUCTS AND SERVICES**

From time to time we may send you information about our Services and/or services offered by third parties in our regular newsletter which is distributed by email or on our website that we think may be of interest to you. You may subscribe to or unsubscribe from the email listserv at any time. This email address is protected from spambots. You may need JavaScript enabled to view it. If you prefer us not to send you our newsletter, you can unsubscribe using the links at the bottom of the email you receive.

**CHANGES TO YOUR DETAILS**

We aim to keep our information about you as accurate as possible. If you would like to review or update your personal information you have supplied us with, you may do so by logging in to your account and visiting the My Account page. You can send mail to the following address: Pathoma LLC 5900 N. Kilpatrick Avenue Chicago, IL 60646.

**WHAT ABOUT THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISERS AND LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES**

Our site includes third-party advertising and links to other Web sites. We do not provide any personally identifiable customer information to these advertisers or third-party Web sites. Third parties have their own privacy policies that govern their use of your information. There may be places on our Site where you may click on a link to access other websites (including social networking services) that don’t operate under this Privacy Policy. These third-party websites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by third parties. Importantly, these third parties will have their own privacy policies describing how they use and disclose your personal information. Those policies will govern the use, handling and disclosure of your personal information once you or we have shared it with those third parties. If you want to learn more about other entities’ privacy practices, please review the websites of those third parties. Privacy policies are typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

**ARE CHILDREN ALLOWED TO USE THE SITE**

Pathoma does not sell products for purchase by children. If you are under 18, you may use the Site only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

**TRANSFERRING YOUR INFORMATION OUTSIDE OF THE U.S.**

As part of our Services, the information you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside of the United States. For example, this may happen if any of our servers are located in a country outside of the United States or one of our service providers is located in a country outside of the United States. We also share information between our group companies, which are located in countries worldwide. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the United States. If we transfer your information outside of the United States in this way, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Similarly, if you use our Services while you are outside the United States, your information may be transferred outside the United States in order to provide you with those Services.

**CONTACT US**

**California Privacy Rights** Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information with respect to the types of personal information the business shares with third parties for direct marketing purposes by such third party and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by Pathoma pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact us using the Contact Form at [http://www.pathoma.com/contact-us](https://www.pathoma.com/contact-us).

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information-handling practices, or if you would like to send an inquiry about our disclosure of personal information to third parties, please contact us using the Contact Form at [http://www.pathoma.com/contact-us](https://www.pathoma.com/contact-us) or via mail at: Pathoma LLC 5900 N. Kilpatrick Avenue Chicago, IL 60646 We will do our best to answer your questions.

**CONDITIONS OF USE, POLICIES AND REVISIONS**

If you choose to visit the Site, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, resolution of disputes, and application of the law of the state of Illinois, in accordance with our Terms of Use. If you have any concern about privacy on the Site, please contact us with a thorough description, and we will try to resolve it. Our business changes constantly, and our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use will change also. You should check our Site frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make, however, and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers.
